lanyrd.com 2018-10-13

# Privacy Policy | Lanyrd

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Lanyrd collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Lanyrd’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Lanyrd’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Lanyrd may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g. by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Lanyrd also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Lanyrd does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Lanyrd choose to interact with Lanyrd in ways that require Lanyrd to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Lanyrd gathers depends on the nature of the interaction.

If a visitor marks themselves as tracking or attending an event, this information is made publicly visible.

Any use of Twitter on behalf of the individual is subject to the [Twitter Terms of Service](http://twitter.com/tos) and [Twitter Privacy Policy](http://twitter.com/privacy). Any use of Linkedin on behalf of the individual is subject to the [Linkedin User Agreement](http://www.linkedin.com/static?key=user_agreement) and [Linkedin Privacy Policy](http://www.linkedin.com/static?key=privacy_policy).

Lanyrd collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfil the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Lanyrd. Lanyrd does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to authenticate with Twitter or Linkedin, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

## Aggregated Statistics

Lanyrd may collect statistics about the behaviour of visitors to its websites. Lanyrd does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

Lanyrd's website uses Google Analytics and KISSmetrics to help collect information about site usage. These services collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including cookies and your IP address. Their usage of this information is governed by their privacy policies.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Lanyrd discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors, and affiliated organisations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Lanyrd’s behalf or to provide services available on Lanyrd, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. 

Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organisations may be located outside of your home country; by using Lanyrd, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. 

Lanyrd will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors, and affiliated organisations, as described above, Lanyrd discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Lanyrd believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Lanyrd, third parties, or the public at large.

If you are a registered user of Lanyrd and have supplied your email address, Lanyrd may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Lanyrd and our products. We primarily use our blog to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Lanyrd will also send you transactional email that you opted into, at the frequency you requested, you can unsubscribe from these at any time. Lanyrd reserves the right to introduce new types of transactional mail which you can then change the frequency of or unsubscribe if you so choose.

Lanyrd would like to reassure you that we will be respectable with the permissions you grant us with your Twitter or LinkedIn accounts. We will never post to Twitter without your _explicit_ permission for us to do so.

Lanyrd takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorised access, use, alteration, or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Lanyrd uses cookies to help Lanyrd identify and track visitors, their usage of Lanyrd website, and their website access preferences.

Lanyrd visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Lanyrd’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Lanyrd’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

You can read more about our usage of cookies here.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Lanyrd may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and at Lanyrd’s sole discretion. Lanyrd encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
